<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="long_info">
        <item>Armenian National Academic Theatre of Opera and Ballet named after Alexander Spendiaryan in Yerevan
            was officially opened on 20 January 1933, with Alexander Spendiaryans Almast
            opera performance. The opera building was designed by the Armenian architect Alexander Tamanian.
            It consists of two concert halls: the Aram Khatchaturian concert hall with 1,400 seats and the Alexander Spendiaryan
            Opera and Ballet National Theatre with 1,200 seats.</item>
        <item>Arno Babajanian was an Armenian composer and pianist during the Soviet era. Babajanian was born in Yerevan, Armenia.
            By age 5, his musical talent was apparent, and the composer Aram Khachaturian suggested that the boy be given proper music training.
            Two years later, in 1928 at the age of 7, Babajanian entered the Yerevan State Musical Conservatory. In 1938, he continued his studies
            in Moscow with Vissarion Shebalin.
            He later returned to Yerevan, where from 1950–1956 he taught at the conservatory. It was during this period
            (1952) that he wrote the Piano Trio in f# sharp minor. It received immediate acclaim and was regarded as a
            masterpiece from the time of its premiere. Subsequently, he undertook concert tours throughout the Soviet Union and Europe.
            In 1971, he was named a People’s Artist of the Soviet Union.
            As a composer, Babajanian was active in most genres and even wrote many popular songs
            in collaboration with the leading poets such as Yevgeny Yevtushenko and Robert Rozhdestvensky among others.
            Much of Babajanian’s music is rooted in Armenian folk music and folklore. But generally, the way in which he uses
            Armenian folk music is in the virtuosic style of Rachmaninov and Khachaturian. His later works were influenced by Prokofiev
            and Bartók. Praised by Dmitri Shostakovich as a "brilliant piano teacher", Babajanian was also a noted pianist and often performed
            his own works in concerts.</item>
        <item>Aram Ilyich Khachaturian was a Soviet Armenian composer and conductor. He is considered one of the leading Soviet composers.
            Born and raised in Tbilisi, the capital of Georgia, Khachaturian moved to Moscow in 1921 following the Sovietization of the Caucasus.
            Without prior music training, he enrolled in the Gnessin Musical Institute, subsequently studying at the Moscow Conservatory in the
            class of Nikolai Myaskovsky, among others. His first major work, the Piano Concerto (1936), popularized his name within and outside
            the Soviet Union. It was followed by the Violin Concerto (1940) and the Cello Concerto (1946). His other significant compositions include
            the Masquerade Suite (1941), the Anthem of the Armenian SSR (1944), three symphonies (1935, 1943, 1947), and around 25 film scores.
            Khachaturian is best known for his ballet music—Gayane (1942) and Spartacus (1954). His most popular piece, the "Sabre Dance" from Gayane,
            has been used extensively in popular culture and has been covered by a number of musicians worldwide. His style is "characterized by colorful harmonies,
            captivating rhythms, virtuosity, improvisations, and sensuous melodies".</item>
        <item>Soghomon Soghomonian, ordained and commonly known as Komitas, was an Armenian priest, musicologist, composer, arranger, singer, and choirmaster,
            who is considered the founder of the Armenian national school of music. He is recognized as one of the pioneers of ethnomusicology.
            Orphaned at a young age, Komitas was taken to Etchmiadzin, Armenias religious center, where he received education at the Gevorgian Seminary.
            Following his ordination as vardapet (celibate priest) in 1895, he studied music at the Frederick William University in Berlin. He thereafter
            "used his Western training to build a national tradition". He collected and transcribed over 3,000 pieces of Armenian folk music, more than
            half of which were subsequently lost and only around 1,200 are now extant. Besides Armenian folk songs, he also showed interest in other cultures
            and in 1904 published the first-ever collection of Kurdish folk songs. His choir presented Armenian music in many European cities, earning the praise
            of Claude Debussy, among others. Komitas settled in Constantinople in 1910 to escape mistreatment by ultra-conservative clergymen at Etchmiadzin and to
            introduce Armenian folk music to wider audiences. He was widely embraced by Armenian communities, while Arshag Chobanian called him the "savior of Armenian music".</item>


    </string-array>
</resources>